So, story time. When I first started getting started with coding,
I was one of those people who thought that JavaScript,
well, in order to know JavaScript,
you need to learn Java.
And this was back in the day where I was learning from an O'Reilly book,
I picked up like an HTML book that my dad had kind of left around.
And then so, when I saw the JavaScript,
I was like, I picked up the Java book instead,
and then I got really confused,
and then I gave up and I was discouraged for many, many years.
But then when I started getting back into it,
then I started learning, okay, so it's different.
And I started working with jQuery,
and then at the round this time,
frameworks are starting to become really big.
So, of course, Angular at this point had really started to get really popular at that point,
and then React came on the scene.
And so, at this point, I'm thinking, okay,
how am I going to get my skills up to date?
And so, I kind of worked with all of these,
and React was the one I'd really been pushing for at one of my old jobs,
when I really first started getting hands-on experience with frameworks.
Because after all, this was at least as far as the statistics show,
the most popular one,
and it gave me a lot of opportunities to practice JavaScript,
so why not?
But what's interesting is that at this company,
even though I was pushing for React,
I had my team going, well, there's this new kid on the block called Vue,
and this is the round time Vue 2 had come out,
that we should really check this out.
It's supposed to be basically just as performant as React,
and it has a more approachable way of building apps.
And for me, I was like, I want to learn the most popular thing,
right, the most cutting edge, so I was incredibly resistant to it.
And so, part of the reason I tell this story is because I want you to know that
this is where I came from,
as far as like, experience working with all these different frameworks,
and then from this context of switching from React to Angular,
into the Vue ecosystem.
And yeah, so we'll go from here.
Okay, so just to make sure we clarify the simple definition of what Vue is,
I think the simplest way to think about it is,
it's a JavaScript framework for building web user interfaces.
That's basically what it is.
It can certainly be used to power other things,
you know, now that we have frameworks that can help you build mobile apps,
you can certainly use it underlying,
but primarily, it's used to build web interfaces.
Now, of course, the big question here is why Vue.js?
Why would people consider using Vue?
The first thing is that it's designed to be approachable,
and what does that mean when we talk about approachable?
And so, this is taken from the docs in that Vue built on top of standard
HTML, CSS, and JavaScript with intuitive API and world-class documentation.
For those coming from the React world,
one of the things you'll know is that,
because one thing React does is it goes all in on your ability to know JavaScript, right?
You have to be able to write basically everything in it,
and things have sort of gotten improved since then,
but especially in the beginning,
you were sort of kept to the conventions of JavaScript
when like you were writing JSX,
so you're writing HTML in your JavaScript,
so you had to do things like class name instead of just class,
because those are like reserved words.
And you found yourself basically contorting the entire website
into what made sense in JavaScript.
And Vue's approach was that why not take what people already know,
HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
and let's just basically build on top of that instead.
And so, as a result, you get a different learning curve,
because I know that when I started with React,
I felt like the amount of JavaScript I needed to really get productive
was super high in terms of knowing a lot of either functional programming
or a lot of the methods in order to loop between elements.
Like, there was a lot going on as far as what's happening in React.
So, there's a decent onboarding curve.
But with Vue, I found that within the first couple of hours,
I was able to get not only onboarded,
but I've taught people who have been out of practice for coding for a long time,
and they got up and running real quick.
And so, we'll get to, I'll show you exactly how that goes,
and we'll get to experience that yourselves.
So, this is one of the things to consider when it comes to Vue.
Performance is always a big thing, especially with frameworks these days.
The big disclaimer I always want to add at first is that
vanilla JavaScript and browser APIs have come a long way.
And so, if you haven't had a chance to check out some of,
I think Mark has a post on redoing to do MVC and vanilla JavaScript,
and so, you know, you might not need a framework.
And I say that as a, you know, a core team member.
But that said, Vue is designed from the ground up
to be a reactive compiler optimized rendering system
that rarely requires manual optimization.
And so, when it comes to performance,
especially the larger your apps get,
a lot of times people are very curious about how we can
basically prevent ourselves from creating bottlenecks in our performance
because we don't understand maybe some of the core primitives about JavaScript,
and that's what frameworks allow for us, right?
They abstract some of that performance away,
so they say, we'll take care of that,
you just write your business logic, and we'll go from there.
And so, you might have noticed too,
I'm not putting any sort of charts or numbers as far as sizes go at this moment
because one of the things that Vue,
and I think a lot of the frameworks are doing right now,
is that they're always trying to find ways to continue to be smaller, right?
And they're learning from each other as we go.
So, when you're deciding whether or not Vue is like the performance framework for you,
especially if you're going to like migrate an enterprise level app,
you're probably going to want to do some benchmarks of your own
because they're going to be different contexts
to why you might be making the decision
because different bottlenecks exist within different contexts.
Okay, the other thing is that Vue is versatile.
So, what does that mean?
So, via the docs, it's a rich, incremental,
adoptable ecosystem that scales between a library and a full-featured framework.
And so, for anyone who's gotten into the discussion,
usually developers get very heated about the library versus framework argument, right?
And that was the big thing for React 2, is React the library,
when is it a framework.
Basically, for Vue, what I would tell you is that it can be used basically as a CDN,
basically as a drop-in library to your page,
which we'll play around with just in a little bit,
or it can be blown up to a fully framework project
that you've come to get familiar with when it comes to front-end applications.
And so, that's basically the difference, I would say, between the two.
That one usually requires build tools, the other one does not.
And so, Vue is really good at doing that.
The other thing that drew me to Vue, especially the more I learned about it,
is that it is community-first.
Something that I think is often overlooked when it comes to Vue is that,
currently, it's just basically within the big three of the frameworks, right?
We have React, Vue, Angular.
And if we think about it, React has Facebook backing it.
We have Google backing Angular.
Yet, Vue is a community-based open-source project
that's managed to climb to the popularity that it has now.
And I think that speaks a lot to the conventions and APIs that were designed
when Vue was built as far as its approachability.
I know people like to jump on the bandwagon
as far as what big tech companies are doing,
but then the fact that Vue was able to do this
while basically learning from different frameworks
and basically helping to do what's best for the community,
I think that's always been a really attractive selling point of Vue,
is because you know that it's driven by doing what's best for the community
rather than what's best for the corporation.
And we've seen trends of that over the community at times,
but that's one of the things I really like about it.
The other thing about Vue is that most of the core team
is actually made up of volunteers across the world.
So I think we have somewhat like 26 different countries of volunteers
basically helping to maintain and build the project.
And that provides for a kind of international perspective
on what's happening in the world as far as different kind of apps.
And so especially when people talk about numbers and popularity,
a lot of things like NPM tend to take statistics
from the Western hemisphere of the world,
but a lot of things in Asia might not be included in that.
And we do know that Vue is heavily used in Asia.
And so it's really cool to see the different kind of perspectives
that come with that.
And so with that, we get a really sort of international mindset
when it comes to building Vue.
Okay.
Of course, that said, people, when they think about Vue,
because it's not backed by Google, it's not backed by Facebook,
they want to know that it's enterprise proven.
And granted, now that it's Vue 3, we've seen a lot of different apps.
I want to just show a couple for those who might not be familiar with this,
but Apple actually used Vue to build their introduction to SwiftUI.
And so the way you know this, by the way,
is if you install Vue DevTools, which I'll show you all how to do later,
you'll notice in the upper right here,
it'll actually detect when Vue is being used and basically flash green.
Otherwise, by flash green, I mean it'll have that enabled state.
Otherwise, it would be grayed out.
And so here's another page.
Here's the Google Careers page where they're also using Vue.
And then some of you might have started using Zoom in the pandemic.
And so, yep, Zoom also uses Vue.
As far as e-commerce goes, we have REIs.
So for all the outdoor people out there when you're using the e-commerce,
Vue is powering that.
L'Oreal Paris as well.
We've had the team actually speak at some of the conferences before,
really fascinating to learn about the different things they're doing
when it comes to makeup.
So some of the things they were doing were like interactive,
basically like imagery where you could change the lipstick,
and then it would change the image color of like the model and stuff like that.
They were doing some really cool stuff as far as reactivity and that kind of thing.
And then here's a fun one, Nintendo.
Nintendo is powered by Vue as well.
So if you're ever logging in, playing around with that,
they are also using Vue.
And if you didn't know, Media Wiki, which is like the big organization
behind Wikipedia as well as some other properties,
they actually did a really long investigation into deciding which framework
they would adopt going forward for their basically migration.
And basically, they landed on Vue, which we were really happy to hear.
And so if you're ever looking to see kind of why they did that,
there's a whole paper on that.
So I just wanted to at least alert you all if you're curious about
like a big organization migrating to Vue and their reasoning behind it.
That is there for you all to read.